A Finding Aid to the Raymond and Margaret Horowitz Papers, 1903-2007, bulk 1960-2007, in the Archives of American Art AAA.hororaym
Archives of American Art
Raymond and Margaret Horowitz papers
bulk 1960-2007
1903-2007
AAA.hororaym
Archives of American Art
5 Linear feet
The papers of collectors Raymond and Margaret Horowitz measure 5.4 linear feet and date from 1903-2007, with the bulk of the material dating from 1960- 2007. The collection documents the Horowitzes' activities as collectors through art collection files, including appraisals, sales information, printed material, and photographs of artwork; files of artwork sold or donated; accession records, including inventory lists of paintings and prints; and catalog information.
Horowitz, Raymond J., 1916-2005
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers of Raymond and Margaret Horowitz were donated in 2015 by Stephen L. Ingerman, the executor of the estate of Raymond and Margaret Horowitz.
Biographical/Historical note
Raymond Horowitz (1916-2005), a lifelong resident of New York City, was a founding partner in the firm Graubard Miller, where he practiced corporate law for over fifty years. Horowitz’s interest in art history and art developed as an undergraduate student at Columbia College (1932-1936) where he attended lectures by the art historian, Meyer Schapiro. In 1939, Horowitz earned his jurisprudence degree from Columbia University. Shortly thereafter, he found a position as assistant Corporation Counsel of the City of New York, where he remained until 1943 when he went into private practice. In 1940, Raymond married Margaret Goldenberg.
Raymond and Margaret shared an interest in art and began collecting in the 1940s. Initially, the Horowitzes acquired drawings and pastels on a modest, informal basis. In 1961, with the purchase of a painting by Robert Henri, Raymond and Margaret began to collect early twentieth century American artists, whose work they thought had been overshadowed by the French Impressionists and the Abstract Expressionists. Raymond and Margaret Horowitz were credited as pioneers in the rediscovery and revaluation of the work of Frank Benson, William Merritt Chase, Childe Hassam, Maurice Prendergast, Theodore Robinson, John H. Twachtman, J. Alden Weir and other notable American Impressionist artists. Raymond Horowitz also acquired the works of Social Realist artists, such as Thomas Anshutz, George Bellows, William Glackens, and John Sloan. Many of the pieces from the Horowitzes' collection have been exhibited in museums and galleries in the United States and abroad. Raymond and Margaret Horowitz donated works of art to the Brooklyn Museum, the Metropolitan Museum of Art, Newark Museum of Art, and the Whitney Museum of American Art; in early 2000s, they made a major gift of 49 paintings, drawings, and watercolors to the National Gallery of Art in Washington, D.C.
In September, 2005, at the age of 90 years, Raymond Horowitz died in New York.
Born in New York City in 1915, Margaret Horowitz (1915-2005) received a Bachelor of Arts degree from New York University. Encouraged by her parents to equip herself to earn a living, Margaret went on to receive a Master’s Degree from Teacher’s College at Fordham University in literature. Raymond Horowitz referred to Margaret as an equal partner in their collecting endeavors. At the time of her death in March, 2005, Margaret and Raymond had been married for sixty-five years.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original material requires an appointment.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of collectors Raymond and Margaret Horowitz measure 5.4 linear feet and date from 1903-2007, with the bulk of the material dating from 1960- 2007. The collection documents the Horowitzes' activities as collectors through art collection files, including appraisals, sales information, printed material, and photographs of artwork; files of artwork sold or donated; accession records, including inventory lists of paintings and prints; and catalog information.
The records document the acquisitions that formed the foundation for the Raymond and Margaret Horowitz collection. Materials reflect Raymond Horowitz's long-standing relationships with dealers, galleries, and museums, including Adelson Galleries, Babcock Galleries, Daniel Fraad, Hirschl & Adler, Paul Magriel, Metropolitan Museum of Art, National Gallery of Art in Washington, D.C., Victor Spark, and others.
Related Archival Materials note
Also found in the Archives of American Art are two oral history interviews with Raymond Horowitz, conducted 1973 January 17 by Paul Cummings and conducted 2004 October 20-November 5 by Avis Berman.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 4 series.
Series 1: Art Collection Files, 1943-2007 (Boxes 1-3; 2.5 linear feet)
Series 2: Artwork, Sold or Donated, 1903, 1950-2003 (Boxes 3-5; 2.0 linear feet)
Series 3: Accession Records, 1959-circa 1994 (Box 5; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 4: Catalog Information, circa 1960-1967 (Box 5; 3 Folders)
Adelson Galleries.; Babcock Galleries.; Fraad, Daniel; Hirschl & Adler Galleries; Horowitz, Margaret, 1915-2005; Magriel, Paul David, 1906-; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.).; National Gallery of Art (U.S.).; Spark, Victor D. (Victor David), 1898-1991; Art--Collectors and collecting--New York (State)--New York; Impressionism (Art); Photographs
- Art Collection Files, 1943-2007; Series 1; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-3
  Scope and Contents note
  Collection files concern the lending, reproduction, and exhibition of works of art owned by Raymond and Margaret Horowitz. Some of the artists significantly represented include William Merritt Chase, William Glackens, Childe Hassam, Robert Henri, Maurice Prendergast, Theodore Robinson, and John Singer Sargent.
  Correspondence reflects Raymond Horowitz’s dealings with museums and galleries, private dealers, and collectors. Among the correspondents are Adelson Galleries, Babcock Galleries, Berry-Hill Galleries, Daniel Fraad, Alfred Frankenstein, Hirschl & Adler Galleries, Paul Magriel, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, National Gallery in London, Newark Museum of Art, Spanierman Gallery, and Yale University Art Gallery. Letters to Antoinette King, Jean Volkmer, and Simon Parkes provide conservation information. Miscellaneous art collection files concern the gifting of artwork to the Metropolitan Museum of Art and the National Gallery in Washington, D.C.
  There are a few letters from Margaret Horowitz. Correspondence is mainly typescripts of originals. Files contain information sheets, appraisals, invoices, condition reports, legal documents relating to loans or donations of artwork, and printed material including exhibition catalogs, invitations, news and magazine clippings of reviews of exhibitions and/or artists. The majority of photographs of artwork have identifying information on the verso that include date of work and exhibition venues.
  Arrangement note
  The series has been maintained in the order it was received. With the exception of American Posters, the series has been arranged in alphabetical order by artist’s surname.
  - American Posters, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anshutz, Thomas - Two Boys By A Boat, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anshutz, Thomas - Woman Drawing, 1963-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Beaux, Cecilia - Portrait of Ethel Page Large, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Beckwith, James C. - Portrait of John Leslie Breck, 1993-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bellows, George - Swans in Central Park, 1967-2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bellows, George - Lithographs, 1968-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bellows, George - Emma in the Purple Dress, 1971-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Benson, Frank - Summer Day, 1968-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Benson, Frank – Elizabeth, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Blum, Robert - The Lace Makers, 1972-1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Blum, Robert - The Blue Obi, 1984-2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bunker, Dennis - Low Tide, 1968-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bunker, Dennis - Roadside Cottage, undated; 1972-2006 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Chase, William Merritt - A Young Woman, 1964-2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chase, William Merritt - Back of Nude, 1965-2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chase, William Merritt - Roses, 1966-2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Chase, William Merritt - Fairy Tale, 1969-2002 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
  - Chase, William Merritt - Self-Portrait, 1969-2003 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Chase, William Merritt - The Artist’s Wife, 1976-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cox, Kenyon - Portrait of Theodore Robinson, 1966-1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Davies, Arthur B. - The Orchard, 1963-1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Duveneck, Frank - Untitled Work, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Elkan, Benno - Abraham, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Glackens, William - Nude, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Glackens, William - The Earmine Muff, 1966-1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Glackens, William - Study of A Young Man, 1967-1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Glackens, William - Seated Woman, 1968-1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Glackens, William - Dinner New Society of Artists, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Hale, Lillian - Japonoiserie, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hardy, Anna Eliza - Still Life Roses, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Harper, William St. John - Reverie, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hassam, Childe - Nurses in the Park, 1961-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hassam, Childe - The White Kimono, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hassam, Childe - Poppies, Isles of Shoals, undated; 1962-2004 (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
  - Hassam, Childe - Young Sappho, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hassam, Childe - Deshabille, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hawthorne, Charles - April, 1966-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Henri, Robert - Girl Seated By the Sea, undated; 1961-2003 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Henri, Robert - Street Scene, Paris, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Henri, Robert - Street Scene, Philadelphia, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Homer, Winslow, Various Works of Art, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - La Farge, John – Wild Roses and Water Lily, 1971-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Lawson, Ernest - Upper Harlem River, 1962-2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Maurer, Alfred H. - At the Shore, 1962-2001 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Maurer, Alfred H. - Café Scene, 1949-1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Metcalf, W. L. - The Jetty, 1963-1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Potthast, Edward - Beach Scene, 1962-1999 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Prendergast, Maurice - Picnic in Central Park, 1962-1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Prendergast, Maurice - The Breezy Common, 1965-1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Prendergast, Maurice - Picnic by the Inlet, circa 1965-2004 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Prendergast, Maurice - Revere Beach, 1972-2003; undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Robinson, Theodore - Self Portrait, undated; 2000; 1943-1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Robinson, Theodore - Young Woman Reading, 1962-1990; undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Robinson, Theodore - Low Tide, Riverside Yacht Club, undated; 1964-2005 (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
  - Robinson, Theodore - A Normandy Mil, 1968-1980; undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Sargent, John Singer - Gondoliers’ Siesta, undated; 1963-1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sargent, John Singer – Gondoliers’ Siesta, undated; 1996-2007 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sargent, John Singer – Under the Willows, undated; 1963-2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Sarka, Charles – “Tetua” Tamarii, Paddling, undated; 1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Shinn, Everett – Matinee, Outdoor Stage, Paris, undated; 1972-2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Shinn, Everett – Girl Cutting Patterns, 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sloan, John – Dolly in Windsor Chair, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sloan, John – Memory, 1968-1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Stella, Joseph – Back of a Woman, Sleeping, 1962-1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Sterne, Maurice – Jeannette, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sterner, Albert – Sketching At The Beach, 1976-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sterner, Albert – Study of A Seated Woman, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Tucker, Allen – The Grey Greek, undated; 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Turner, Charles Yardley – Woman Picking Blossoms, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Twachtman, John H. - Waterfront Scene, Gloucester, 1966-1988; undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Twachtman, John H. - Trees in a Nursery, 1967-1989; undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Twachtman, John H. - September Sunshine, 1995-2000 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Vonnoh, Robert - Springtime in France, undated; 1962-2001 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Weir, J. Alden, - U.S. Thread Company, Willamatic, Connecticut, 1968-2000; undated (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - Weir, J. Alden - Portrait of Miss Hoe, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Weir, J. Alden – Roses, 1981-1997; undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Whistler, James McNeil – La Belle Dame Endormie, 1982-2003; undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Whistler, James McNeil – The Toilet and Study: Seated Figure, 1985-2005 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Art Collection Files - Appraisals
    - Hassam, Childe - Poppies, Isles of Shoals, 1992-2003 (Box 3, Folder 24-26)
    - Prendergast, Maurice – Picnic By The Inlet, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Weir, J. Alden – U.S. Thread Company, Willamatic, Connecticut, 1977-1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Artwork, Sold, or Donated, 1903; 1950-2003; Series 2; 2 Linear feet Boxes 3-5
  Records document sales, acquisitions, donations, and the lending of artwork for exhibitions. Included are extensive files on George Bellows, Robert Blum, Frank Boggs, Willilam Merritt Chase, Willliam Glackens, A. C. Goodwin, Theodore Robinson, John Singer Sargent, and John H. Twachtman. Materials also document Raymond Horowitz' s collecting interests and his professional and, to a lesser extent his personal relationships with auction houses, dealers, museums, and collectors. Among the correspondents are Adelson Galleries, Berry-Hill Galleries, Inc., Christie’s, Hollis-Taggart Galleries, M. Knoedler & Co., Inc., Parke Bernet (Sotheby’s), and Whitney Museum of American Art. Miscellaneous paintings consists of a consignment agreement with Hirschl & Adler.
  Files include correspondence, information sheets, appraisals, receipts and invoices, and other legal documentation, including contracts, loan agreements, consignments, and settlement statements. Included are printed materials, exhibition catalogs, clippings of reviews, photographs, and negatives.
  The series has been maintained in the order it was received. The series has been arranged in alphabetical order by artist’s surname.
  - Anshutz, Thomas – Studies of Two Heads, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Anshutz, Thomas – Woman in a Pink Dress on Beach, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Anshutz, Thomas – Boat and Boathouse, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Beal, Gifford – Running Horses, undated; 1950-1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Beal, Gifford – Harbor, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Beaux, Cecilia – Dorothea In The Woods, undated; 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Beaux, Cecilia – Henry James, undated; 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Beckwith, Carroll – A Woman In A Boat, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Bellows, George - Draped Male Figure Standing, 1962-1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Bellows, George - The Dreamer, 1963-1986 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Bellows, George - The Beach, 1964-1973 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Bellows, George – Irishman Leaning on Chair, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Bellows, George – The Village on the Hill, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Bellows, George - Ox Team Matinicus, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Bellows, George – Portrait of Eugene Speicher, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Bellows, George – Nude, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Blum, Robert - View From The Artist’s Window, 1963-1977 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Blum, Robert - Geisha Girl, 1963-1985 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Blum, Robert – Circus Ring At Night, 1964-1975 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Blum, Robert – Men Fishing, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Boggs, Frank – Armistice Day, Paris, 1964-1971 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Boggs, Frank – The Church of Dunkirk, 1964-1977 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Boggs, Frank – Crossing the River, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Boggs, Frank – Marine, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Boggs, Frank – Shipping, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Boggs, Frank – Pont Neuf, 1963-1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bourdelle, Antoine – Sculptress Resting, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Breck, John Leslie – Portrait of Blanche Hosché dé-Monet, undated; 1977-1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Butler, Theodore - Jardin, Maison Baptiste, 1967-1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Candell, Victor – Port O’Call, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Carles, Arthur B. – On the Terrace, Venice, 1962-1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cassatt, Mary – The Letter, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chase, William Merritt – Marine, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chase, William Merritt – Shinnecock Hills, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chase, William Merritt – Prospect Park, Brooklyn, circa 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chase, William Merritt – Portrait of E. G. Kennedy, 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chase, William Merritt – Tenth Street Studio, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Chase, William Merritt – Portrait of Mrs. Chase, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Chase, William Merritt – Portrait of Mrs. Wase, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chase, William Merritt – Reflection, 1982-2003 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Chase, William Merritt – Self-Portrait Monotype, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Cooper, Colin Campbell – The Capitol At Night, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Cooper, Colin Campbell – View of New York City, 1967-1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Crosby, Raymond – Seated Woman, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Davies, Arthur B. – Reclining Nude, 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Davies, Arthur B. – Seated Figure, 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Davies, Arthur B. – Italian Landscape II, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Davies, Arthur B. – Woodland Scene, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - De Camp, Joseph – Beach in France, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Dewing, Thomas – May Morning, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Dewing, Thomas – Portrait Of A Lady, circa 1969-1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Dickinson, Edwin – Nude, Provincetown, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Dielman, Frederick – Girl In The Field, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Dinnerstein, Harvey - Porch, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Dreier, Dorothea – Flower Picking, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Fisher, Mark – The Artist’s Wife, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Gauley, Robert – Intervale, New Hampshire, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Glackens, William – Woman In Hat, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Glackens, William – Figure On A Ferryboat, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Glackens, William – Park By The East River, 1961-1976 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Glackens, William – At The Milliner’s, 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Glackens, William – Flowers In A Pompeian Vase, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Glackens, William – Fifth Avenue Bus, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Glintenkamp, Henry – Woman On Stoop, 1963-1976 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Goldthwaite, Anne – Children in Luxembourg Gardens, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Goodwin, A. C. – Public Gardens, Boston (Oil), 1962-1967 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Goodwin, A. C. – Public Gardens, Boston (Pastel), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Goodwin, A. C. – The Grundeman Studios, Copley Hall, Boston, 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Goodwin, A. C. – Celebration of Armistice Day, 1918, 1965-1980 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Goodwin, A. C. – Dartmouth Street From Copley Square, circa 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Halpert, Samuel – Paris Scene, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Hart, George O. – Boardwalk, Atlantic City, 1961-1999 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Hassam, Childe – Central Park at 59th Street, 1900, undated; 1964-1979 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Hassam, Childe – Monet’s House, 1964-1979 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Hawthorne, Charles W. – Highland Light, 1961-1966 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Hawthorne, Charles W. – The Shipwright, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Henri, Robert – Strollers Rest, undated; 1954-1978 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Henri, Robert – The Café Terrace, undated; 1963-1998 (Box 4, Folder 55-56)
  - Henri, Robert – Absinthe Drinker, 1964-1980 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Henri, Robert – Man and Woman Laughing, 1965-1976 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Henri, Robert – Paris Street Scene, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Hirsch, Joseph – Coffee Cakes, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Koch, John – Study For Pink Dressing Gown, 1961-1976 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Kuhn, Walt – Clown With Bug, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - La Farge, John – View From Hut, At Vaiala in Upolu, 1971-1986 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Lang, Annie T. – Portrait of William Merritt Chase, 1977-1985 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Lever, Hayley – Along The Thames, London, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Lever, Hayley – A Windy Day, St. Ives, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Lever, Hayley – Boats In A Harbor, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Lever, Hayley – Hyde Park, The Row, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Lever, Hayley – Boats In Sunlight, St. Ives, 1962-1989 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Lie, Jonas – Tuna Boats, 1972-1984 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Luks, George – Jack-O-Lantern, 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Luks, George – Dressing Room, 1961-1976 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Macrae, Elmer L. – Boats At Landing, 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Macrae, Elmer L. – Group At the Beach, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Martin, Homer D. – Ned Samson and His Wife, 1966-1967; undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Maurer, Alfred – Paysage Vert Et Rose, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Maurer, Alfred – Femme Aux Cheveux Rouges, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Metcalf, Willard L. – Portrait of Marguerite, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Metcalf, Willard L. – Venetian Scene, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Metcalf, Willard L. – Summer At Walberswick, 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Mora, F. Luis – Mrs. F. Luis Mora and Her Sister, undated; 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Mora, F. Luis – A Seated Lady, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Morgan, Wallace - Untitled Painting, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Morisot, Berthe – Girl Seated, Writing, circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Myers, Jerome – Second Avenue Park, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Myers, Jerome – The Market Women, Paris, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Myers, Jerome – Street Scene, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Myers, Jerome – Peddlers On Lower East Side, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Perry, Lilla Cabot – Lady In Black, 1979-1985 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Peterson, Jane – After The Race, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Picknell, William L. – From My Studio Window, undated; 1968-1997 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Potthast, Edward H. – Beach At Ostend, undated; 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Potthast, Edward H. – Children At Fountain, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Potthast, Edward H. – Figure Drawing, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Prendergast, Maurice – On The Beach, 1962-1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Prendergast, Maurice – Revere Beach, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Preston, James – Haystacks, 1960-1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Ranger, Henry Ward – Harbor Scene, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Robinson, Theodore – Valley Of The Seine, 1961-1975; undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Robinson, Theodore – Fishing Huts in France, 1962-1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Robinson, Theodore – The Hills, 1962-1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Robinson, Theodore – The Cabbage Patch, 1962-1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Robinson, Theodore – Etude, 1962-1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Robinson, Theodore – From The Hill, Giverny, 1963-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Robinson, Theodore – Autumn Sunlight, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Robinson, Theodore – Untitled Drawing, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Robinson, Theodore – Miscellaneous Clippings, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Sargent, John Singer – Young Girl, 1961-1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Sargent, John Singer – By The Fire, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Sargent, John Singer – Lady Seated Beside An Alpine Pool, 1968-1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)